kotlin a statically typed multi-paradigm language designed quite simply as a
kotlin 一种静态类型的多范式语言，其设计非常简单，是
better alternative to java like java it compiles to bytecode that runs on the
java 的一种更好的替代方案，例如 java 它编译为在 java 虚拟机上运行的字节码，
java virtual machine but kotlin provides a more concise syntax and language
但 kotlin 提供了更简洁的语法和
features loved by modern developers like type inference functional patterns null
现代开发人员喜爱的语言特性，如类型推断功能模式 null
safety and more it was announced in 2011 by jetbrains with the first stable
安全性和更多它是 2011 年由 jetbrains 宣布的，第一个稳定
release coming in 2016. it's named after kotlin island in russia and it just got
版本将于 2016 年发布。它以俄罗斯的科特林岛命名，
a mascot in october 2021 but it still doesn't have a name yet one of its key
2021 年 10 月刚刚获得吉祥物，但它仍然没有名字，这是它的主要
features is that it can interop with existing java code which means
功能之一 是它可以与现有的 java 代码互操作，这意味着
developers can gradually adopt it without throwing all of their code in
开发人员可以逐渐采用它，而不会将所有代码
the garbage in addition to jvm kotlin can also compile to native code and
都扔进垃圾箱中，此外 jvm kotlin还可以编译为本机代码和
javascript opening the door to multi-platform apps it's been most
javascript，为多平台应用程序打开了大门，它是最
influential in the android development community and as of 2019 google named it
有影响力的 在 android 开发社区中，截至 2019 年，谷歌将其命名
the preferred language for android development over java one of its killer
为 android 开发的首选语言，而不是其 k 之一的 java  iller
features is co-routines which provides a simplified way to write asynchronous
功能是协同例程，它提供了一种编写异步
non-blocking code a common requirement for mobile developers to get started
非阻塞代码的简化方法 移动开发人员开始的常见要求
create a file ending in.kt most kotlin developers use something like intellij
创建一个以.kt 结尾的文件 大多数 kotlin开发人员使用类似
idea which is an ide brought to you by the same company that invented the
intellij idea 的东西，这是由在文件中发明语言的同一家公司
language inside the file use the fun keyword to define a main function this
使用 fun关键字定义主函数 这
is where your code will start executing and that syntax is a lot more fun to
是您的代码将开始执行的地方，并且该语法
write than public static void main string args declare a variable with the
比 public static void mainstring args 使用 var 声明变量更有趣
var keyword assign a value and its type will be inferred automatically or you
关键字分配一个值，它的类型将被自动推断，或者您
can add a colon after the variable name with an explicit type a variable can't
可以在具有显式类型的变量名称后添加一个冒号，
be null unless you explicitly allow it with a question mark on the type now use
除非您在类型上使用问号明确允许它，否则变量不能为空 现在使用
printline to log the variable to the standard output notice how semicolons
printline 记录标准输出的变量 注意分号
are optional which means that line breaks are significant kotlin supports
是可选的，这意味着换行很重要 kotlin 支持
familiar object-oriented patterns but can do special functional things that
熟悉的面向对象模式，但可以做 spe  java 不能喜欢的 cial 功能性事物
java cannot like modify the behavior of a class without inheritance using
不使用扩展函数继承来修改类的行为
extension functions functions are first class objects which means they can be
函数是第一类对象，这意味着它们可以
stored as variables passed as arguments or used anonymously with lambdas kotlin
存储为作为参数传递的变量或与 lambdas 匿名使用 kotlin
also reduces boilerplate with things like data classes so you don't have to
还减少了诸如数据类之类的样板文件，因此您 不必
write constructors getters and setters and supports destructuring when
编写构造函数 getter 和 setter并在
accessing the values on an object allowing you to write concise efficient
访问对象上的值时支持解构，从而允许您编写简洁高效的
code that you can then compile to a jar file by pulling up the terminal and
代码，然后您可以通过拉起终端并
running the kotlin compiler this has been kotlin in 100 seconds hit the like
运行 kotlin 编译器将其编译为 jar 文件 这一直是 kotlin 在 100 秒内点击喜欢
button and subscribe if you want to see more short videos like this thanks for
按钮并订阅如果您想看更多这样的短视频感谢
watching and i will see you in the next one
观看，我会在下一个看到你